Manoj Tiwari

San Francisco Bay Area



manoj41@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/manoj-tiwari-17b9213

Summary

I am a dedicated and collaborative professional who is best known for my ability to work effectively with my colleagues. I believe that communication and teamwork are key to achieving success, and I always strive to build strong relationships with those around me.

I have a strong aversion to pushy people, and I believe that success comes from fostering a positive and supportive work environment. My greatest strength is my ability to quickly and easily identify the skills, gifts, and talents of those around me, and to help them develop and utilize those strengths.

In my free time, I enjoy playing chess, which allows me to clear my mind and focus on strategy and problem-solving. I also enjoy using my skills and experience to help others, through mentoring, writing, presentations and workshops. I believe that by exploring our pasts, we can create a better future for ourselves and those around us.

- "Written with help from chatGPT"

Experience

G Senior Engineering Manager, Google Research

Google

Jun 2019 - Present (3 years 8 months)

- Led a team of ~12 Googlers which included a junior manager, four senior staff engineers & other researchers.
- Youtube search with LLMs: Built 'explainable' and 'controllable' recommendation system with large language model.
- Built personalized model training infrastructure which is capable of processing X billion user timelines composed of Search, YouTube, Chrome & other activities. System was adopted by 30+ teams including Ads, Search, Shopping, etc. and received 'Google Research Technical Impact Award' in 2022.

G Tech Lead/Staff Software Engineer

Google

Jul 2014 - Jun 2019 (5 years)

Delivered multiple Machine Learning projects in Google Research:

- Neural net models for Google Assistant fast checkout: https://9to5google.com/2021/07/28/google-assistant-fast-checkout/
- Neural Network based personalized recommendation model for 10+ Google Products including Play apps, books, movies, Search, YouTube serving X billion users leading to +Y billion interactions & + \$777 million revenue.

Senior Software Engineer

Google

Oct 2012 - Jun 2014 (1 year 9 months)

* Built Software Defined Networking (SDN) control plane infrastructure for Google's data center via Jupiter Fabric: https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/systems/the-evolution-of-googles-jupiter-data-center-network

Staff Engineer

Juniper Networks

May 2010 - Dec 2012 (2 years 8 months)

- * Built Juniper's Data Center switch Q-FABRIC with distributed control plane.
- * Implemented distributed BGP protocol for control plane infrastructure.
- * Integrated Q-FABRIC and MX series routers for seamless routing.

Software Engineer

Redback Networks

May 2005 - May 2010 (5 years 1 month)

- * Built shared memory routing infrastructure (RIB and FIB) for routers/switches.
- * Implemented Netflow V5, V9 and IPFIX for routers/switches.
- * Implemented Lawful intercept feature to comply with US Government regulations.

Software Engineer

Infosys

Jun 2003 - May 2005 (2 years)

- * Supported world wide deployment on Cable Model Termination System.
- * Implemented DHCP Relay agent in Cable Model Termination System.

Education



Stanford University

Advanced Software Systems Graduate Certificate

2010 - 2013

Distributed Systems, Object Oriented Programming, Adv. Operating System & Distributed Data Management.



Devi Ahilya Vishwavidyalaya

Masters of Tech., Embedded Systems



Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University, Aurangabad

B.Tech, Computer Science and Engg

Skills

Leadership Development • Software Development • Software Defined Networking • Interdisciplinary Collaboration • C++ • Mentoring • Product Development • Cross-team Collaboration • Machine Learning • Team Leadership